Guide to the Harold Schmidt Collection ARS.0120
Archive of Recorded Sound
- 1. Tapes, reel
  - Stanford Choir, Chorale performances (chronological)
    - Berlioz, Requiem. SF Symphony, Stanford, Ozawa, 1972-03-31; 2 7" open reel tapes (Audio 7, Audio 5)
    - Easter Service, Memorial Church [program enclosed], 1972-04-02; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Choir. Public Worship Service. Ligeti, Mechem, 1972-05-07; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Chorale. Vecchi, 1972-06-05; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - 10/1-11/12. Choir, Public Worship Service [programs enclosed], 1972; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 10)
    - Choir, Public Worship Service. 11/19/72-1/28/73 [programs enclosed], 1972-1973; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 10)
    - Christmas. Organ Tape 1, 1972-12-08; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - Choir, Monteverdi, Magnificat, 1972-12-08; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Stanford Chorale, Sequoias, 1972-12-15; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
    - Chorale. Museum Tape 3, 1972-12-19; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - Choir. A-B-C, 1973; 3 7" open reel tapes (Audio 1)
    - Choir, Spring, 1973; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - 2/11-3/18. Choir, Public Worship Service [programs enclosed], 1973; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 10)
    - Mozart, Requiem. Rehearsal, Memorial Church, 1973-03-10; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
    - Founder's Day Concert. Stanford University Chorus, Chamber Orchestra. Memorial Church [program enclosed], 1973-03-11; 2 7" open reel tapes (Audio 8)
    - Choir, 1973-04-08; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - Choir, 1973-04-15; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - Choir, 1974-04-20; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - Choir, Easter Sunday, 1973-04-22; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - Choir, 1973-04-29; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - University Chorus, Stanford Chorale, University Choir. Gala Spring Concert. Dinkelspiel, 1973-05-25; 3 7" open reel tapes (Audio 8)
    - Museum Concert. Blow; Bach; Mozart, 1973-08-07; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - Christmas Concert, Dubbing?, 1973-12-07; 2 7" open reel tapes (Audio 10)
    - Memorial Church Choir and Orchestra. Handel, Messiah, 1974-12-07; 2 7" open reel tapes (Audio 10)
    - 1/12-2/9. Choir, 1975; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - Choir 2/12-3/16, 1975; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 3)
    - Choir, 1975-03-09; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - Choir, 1975-03-30; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - Choir, 1975-04-06; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - Choir, 1975-04-13; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - 4/27-5/11. Choir, 1975; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - Verdi, Requiem Rehearsal. University Chorus, Memorial Church Choir, Stanford Chorale. Dinklespiel, 1975-05-01; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - 6/1-6/29. Choir, 1975; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - Choir, 1975-07-20; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
  - Stanford Orchestra, Salgo. Schmidt, Tenor. Debussy. Special, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
  - [Stravinsky,] Rakes Progress Reel 2, 3, 1955-05-27; 2 10.5" open reel tapes (Audio 1)
  - Student recitals
    - Winston Wing Ming Seal [recitals?], 1973-1974; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Shuhei Seyama [recitals?], 1974; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Myles Y. Shimokawa, 1974; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Michael John Sobolik [recitals?], 1974-06; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Jose L. Villalobos [recitals?], 1974-06; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Recitals Vol. VI. Tracy Fletcher, Elisabeth Rundlette, Katherine Nielsen. California State, Northridge [programs enclosed], 1987-1989; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - Verdi, Requiem, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 2)
  - Verdi, Requiem, 1975-05-11; 2 7" open reel tapes (Audio 6)
  - [Wagner,] Lohengrin, Act III. O'Neal, Hajossova, Adam, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
  - Elinor Remick Warren, The Legend of King Arthur. Los Angeles Master Chorale And Sinfonia Orchestra [printed label], 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
  - Vaughn Williams, 1973-03-04; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 8)
  - Vaughn Williams, Serenade; Stravinsky, Cantata, 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
  - Vaughn Williams. This Day, Hodie - 1954, 1958-12-07; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  - Unidentified
    - [unidentified, probably Curt Allen], 2 3" open reel tapes (Audio 10)
    - 1328-1329 [illeg.], 2 7" open reel tapes (Audio 3, Audio 4)
    - [illeg.] Check It Out, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - 4-5, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 4)
    - unlabeled Ampex 400 Mastering Tape, 2 10.5" open reel tapes (Audio 1)
    - Marc, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - W-10, 1965-01-29; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - H.O. #34 11/10-12/8, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - T.O. #1 6/30-9/29, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Is This Rochberg?, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - April 28, 1st Time; April 30, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 7)
    - Lipa, Orthapedics, 1962-08-25; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Instrumental No.24, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 5)
    - Tape 2 of May 28. Vocal Chorus. M-ta7 23, 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 6)
    - Symphony, 1980-01-02; 1 5" open reel tape (Audio 7)
  - Commercial copies, aircheck copies, class and lecture recordings (probably excerpts), completely unmarked tapes, etc. (Audio 11)
- 2. Tapes, cassette, 40 audiocassettes (Audio 12)
  Scope and Contents
  Most cassettes are minimally labeled. A sampling of some of the more descriptive titles: Keltenborn; Stephen and Brandon Reading 1975-76; Druckman: Prism; Haydn Through American Music 8/8/75; Brant, Solomon's Gardens 8/8/75; William Walton, Scenes. Schwarzkopf, Lewis; Berlioz, Benvenuto Cellini; Barbara Wright Schmidt Memorial at Stanford Memorial Church 11/10/88; Otto Ketting, Symphony No.1; Henze, SF Symphony 2/2/79; Haydn Te Deum; Chichester Psalm; Stanford Chorale, Christmas at Sequoias 1973; Liszt, NY Philharmonic, Boulez 1971; Schumann, SF Symphony 2/2/79; Erb, Erase; Complete Concert 8/9/74; Choir 12/6/74
- 3. Discs (instantaneous discs and test pressings)
  - [unidentified] (National), 1 10" instantaneous disc (Audio 9)
  - 1st not copy; 2nd not copy [unidentified] (Presto), 1 12" instantaneous disc (Audio 9)
  - 1st, 2nd, 3rd, 4th [unidentified] (Presto, glass), 2 12" instantaneous discs (Audio 9)
  - Alleluia From King David, Final Chorus (Audiodisc), 1 12" instantaneous disc (Audio 9)
  - Arise; Last Words; Silent Prayer; Psalm; Mendelssohn; Holst; Amen (Audio Associates), 1 12" instantaneous disc (Audio 9)
  - Bach B Minor (Sound Recorders, San Francisco), 1 12" instantaneous disc (Audio 9)
  - Christmas Carol; While By My Sheep; Kyrie Eleison, Imperfect (Presto), 1 12" instantaneous disc (Audio 9)
  - Couperin (Presto, glass), 2 12" instantaneous discs (Audio 9)
  - D'Anna (KSU Transcription), 1 12" instantaneous disc (Audio 9)
  - Hallelujah; Credo (Presto, glass), 1 12" instantaneous disc (Audio 9)
  - Hassler, Cantate Domini (Radio Recorders), 1 10" instantaneous disc (Audio 9)
  - Hay Un Ritmo; Tutu Maramba; Na Bahia [illeg.] (Presto, glass), 1 12" instantaneous disc (Audio 9)
  - Jones (KSU Transcription), 2 12" instantaneous discs (Audio 9)
  - King David: Now My Voice; Pity Me God (Audiodisc), 1 12" instantaneous disc (Audio 9)
  - Kyrie Eleison; Ferrero No.2 (Presto, glass), 1 12" instantaneous disc (Audio 9)
  - Kyrie Eleison, Mauricio (Presto, glass), 1 12" instantaneous disc (Audio 9)
  - Let Us Sing (Audio Devices), 1951-11-27; 1 12" instantaneous disc (Audio 9)
  - Love Took Me Softly By THe Hand; Eyes Hide My Love, HCS; Inventor Rotuli; Eyes Hide My Love; A Maiden Journey'd, HCS (Presto), 1 12" instantaneous disc (Audio 9)
  - Morning Star; While By My Sheep; Ave Verum, Byrd (Presto), 1 12" instantaneous disc (Audio 9)
  - Peter Grimes (Audio Devices) [probably Stanford Players, Memorial Auditorium, May 27-29, 1948], 6 12" instantaneous discs (Audio 9)
  - Piston (Presto, Audiodisc), 1942; 2 12" instantaneous discs (Audio 9)
  - Sample: Piston, Couperin (Presto, glass), 1 12" instantaneous disc (Audio 9)
  - Stanford Easter Services, NBC (NBC Orthacoustic), 1952-04-13; 2 12" instantaneous discs (Audio 9)
  - Stanford Memorial Church Choir, Schmidt (Audio Associates), 1956-12-07; 1 12" instantaneous disc (Audio 9)
  - Topham (KSU Transcription), 1 12" instantaneous disc (Audio 9)
  - University Chorus. Spring Returns; Agnus Dei (KSU Transcription), 1 12" instantaneous disc (Audio 9)
  - Vaughn Williams VLPST-1003 Stamper Test (Recorders Lab, Inc.), 1 10" vinyl disc (Audio 9)
  - WRS-1475 7/25/75; WRS-1575 7/25/75; WRS-1675 7/31/75 [white labels, handwritten information], 1975-07; 3 vinyl discs: 1 7"; 2 12" (Audio 9)
- 4. Slides, photographs, video (Box 12)
  Four smaller boxes and one larger box. Images of Memorial Church, singers and orchestra (including a 12/10/74 museum performance and a Gluck opera), and some of family and nature. Video reels are Sony V-30H. One is of the Stanford Choir dated 12/73, the other is a Hewlett-Packard release of "The Sound of the Season: 1973 Christmas Show" featuring the Stanford Choir as well as greetings from Bill Hewlett and Dave Packard.